Taylor, J. mss., 1975-1998 LMC 2419
Lilly Library
Taylor, J. mss.
1975-1998
Lilly Library
Taylor, Jeri
LMC 2419
12 Boxes
The Taylor, J. mss., 1975-1996, consist of the papers of television producer and script writer Jeri Taylor, 1938-, an Indiana University alumnus.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Jeri Taylor, 1938-, was an executive producer and contributing writer of the television series Star Trek: The Next Generation and Star Trek: Voyager.
Taylor was born in Evansville, Indiana in 1938. She received her BA in English from Indiana University in 1959 and her MA in English from California State University, Northridge. During the 1980s she worked as a television writer and producer, working on shows such as Little House on the Prairie and The Incredible Hulk.
She joined Star Trek: The Next Generation as a supervising producer at the beginning of its fourth season. She worked as a co-executive producer for the sixth season and executive producer for the seventh and final season. She also co-created Star Trek: Voyager with Rick Berman and Michael Piller and worked as executive producer for the first four seasons. In addition, she has written three Star Trek novels.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: Star Trek: The Next Generation, Star Trek: Voyager, and Additions, 1999.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of outlines, scripts, technical notes, cast lists, and some shooting schedules for the 7th and final season of The Next Generation, 1993-1994, and draft scripts, casting call sheets, research notes, etc. for Voyager, 1994-1996. Some of the outlines, technical notes, and lists carry her annotated changes or comments.
Copies of final scripts for all seasons of Star Trek: The Next Generation have been separately cataloged and are housed in the Lilly Library printed collections (Lilly: PN6120.S48 S796).
The collection also includes scripts written by Jeri Taylor for televisions series on which she was story editor, co-writer, or occasionally producer. These series include In the Heat of the Night, Jake and the Fatman, Magnum P.I., and Quincy, M.E. Also present are scripts written and sold as a free-lance writer for the series California Fever, The Incredible Hulk, Little House on the Prairie, and Salvage.
The final subseries, Development, consists of scripts and story ideas, largely unproduced, written during what Jeri Taylor describes as "development hell" at Norman Lear's Embassy Productions from 1985-1987.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1994, 1995, 1997, 1998
Television; Star Trek television programs; Indiana University -- Alumni and alumnae; Taylor, Jeri
- Star Trek: The Next Generation (Season 7)
  Arrangement
  Arranged by show number, title of episode and date of final script.
  - 153. Descent, Part II, June 24, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 154. Liaisons, July 6, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 155. Interface, July 14, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 156. Gambit, Part I, July 26, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 157. Gambit, Part II, Aug. 6, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 158. Phantasms, Aug. 17, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 159. Dark Page, Aug. 26, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 160. Attached, Sept. 7, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 161. Force of Nature, Sept. 17, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 162. Inheritance, Sept. 27, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 163. Parallels, Oct. 7, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 164. The Pegasus, Oct. 18, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 165. Homeward, Oct. 27, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 165. Sub Rosa (formerly known as Passions), Nov. 5, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 167. Lower Decks, Nov. 17, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 168. Thine Own Self (formerly known as Jayden), Nov. 30, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 169. Masks, Dec. 9, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 170. Eye of the Beholder, Dec. 20, 1993; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 171. Genesis, Jan. 7, 1994; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 172. Journey's End, Jan. 20, 1994; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 173. Firstborn, Jan. 28, 1994; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 174. Bloodlines, Feb. 9, 1994; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 175. Emergence, Feb. 17, 1994; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 176. Preemptive Strike (formerly known as The Good Fight), Mar. 1, 1994; (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - 177. All Good Things..., Mar. 10, 1994; (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - 177. All Good Things... (cont.), (2 folders) (Box 3)
- Star Trek: Voyager (Seasons 1-4)
  Arranged by show number, title of episode, and date of final script after the pilot episode.
  General
  Call sheets for the series complete this section.
  - Season 1
    - 721. Caretaker, Sept. 20, 1994; (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - 103. Parallax (formerly known as Deep Time), Oct. 11, 1994; (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 104. Time and Again, Oct. 27, 1994; (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 105. Phage (formerly known as Heart & Soul), Nov. 11, 1994; (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 106. The Cloud, Nov. 22, 1994; (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 107. Eye of the Needle, Nov. 23, 1994; (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 108. Ex Post Facto, Dec. 9, 1994; (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 109. Emanations (formerly known as Beyond), Jan. 6, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 110. Prime Factors, Jan. 13, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 111. State of Flux (formerly known as Seska), Jan. 25, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 112. Heroes and Demons, Feb. 2, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 113. Cathexis (formerly known as Intruder Alert), Feb. 17, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 114. Faces [Purification], Feb. 24, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 115. Jetrel, Mar. 8, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 116. Learning Curve, Mar. 21, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Season 2
    - 117. Projections, Mar. 30, 1995; (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - 118. Elogium (formerly known as The Alamak; The Running), [], Apr. 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
      No Final Draft
    - 119. Twisted (formerly known as Out), Apr. 21, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 120. The 37's, May 1, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 121. Initiations, July 10, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 122. Non Sequitur, July 19, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 123. Parturition (formerly known as Fog; Echolocation), July 24, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 124. Persistence of Vision (formerly known as Untitled Janeway), Aug. 4, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 125. Tattoo (formerly known as First World), Aug. 11, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 126. Cold Fire (formerly known as Untitled Kes Firebug), Aug. 30, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 127. Maneuvers (formerly known as Manipulations), Sept. 11, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 128. Resistance (formerly known as Merrek), Sept. 20, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 129. Prototype, Sept. 29, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 130. Death Wish (formerly known as Untitled Q), Oct. 9, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 131. Alliances (formerly known as Untitled Kazon), Oct. 18, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 132. Threshold (formerly known as Untitled Warp 10), Oct. 31, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 133. Meld, Nov. 7, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 134. Dreadnought (formerly known as Counterstrike; Original Sin), Nov. 16, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 135. Investigations (formerly known as Untitled Neelix Newspaper; The Right to Know), Dec. 1, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 136. Lifesigns (formerly known as Untitled Doctor; Magnetism), Dec. 13, 1995; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 137. Deadlock, Jan. 3, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 138. Innocence (formerly known as Untitled Tuvok; Emotional Awakening), Jan. 10, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 139. The Thaw, Jan. 19, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 140. Tuvix (formerly known as Untitled Tuvok/Neelix; One; Symbiogenesis), Feb. 2, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 141. Resolutions, Feb. 7, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 142. Basics, Part I, Feb. 23, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Season 3
    - 143. Sacred Ground, Mar. 5, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 144. False Profits (formerly known as The Visitors; Penitence; Untitled Ferengi Story), Mar. 15, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 145. Flashback, Mar. 26, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 146. Basics, Part II, Apr. 2, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 147. The Chute (formerly known as The Playground), July 3, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 148. Remember, July 16, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - 149. The Swarm (formerly known as The Patient), July 26, 1996; (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - 150. Future's End, Part I, Aug. 5, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 151. Future's End, Part II, Aug. 15, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 152. Warlord (formerly known as The Art of War), Aug. 28, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 153. The Q and the Grey, Sept. 10, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 154. Macrocosm, Sept. 19, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 155. Alter Ego, Sept. 27, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 156. Fair Trade (formerly known as Old Scores), Oct. 7, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 157. Blood Fever, Oct. 18, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 158. Coda (formerly known as Fractals), Oct. 29, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 159. Unity, Nov. 7, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 160. Rise!, Nov. 19, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 161. The Darkling, Dec. 3, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 162. Favorite Son (formerly known as Heritage), Dec. 12, 1996; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 163. Before and After, Jan. 6, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 164. Real Life, Jan. 15, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 165. Distant Origin, Jan. 23, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 166. Displaced, Feb. 5, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 167. Worst Case Scenario (formerly known as Novelty), Feb. 14, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 168. Scorpion, Part I (Box 8)
      No materials received.
  - Season 4
    - 169. Scorpion, Part II, May 23, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 170. The Gift, June 4, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 171. Nemesis (formerly known as The Recruit), June 13, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 172. Day of Honor, June 25, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 173. Revulsion (formerly known as Delirium), July 7, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 174. The Raven (formerly known as Resurrection), July 16, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 175. Scientific Method (formerly known as Tagged), July 25, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 176. Year of Hell, Aug. 5, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 177. Year of Hell, Part II, Aug. 15, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 178. Random Thoughts, Aug. 26, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 179. Concerning Flight (formerly known as DaVinci's Day Out), Sept. 5, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 180. Mortal Coil, Sept. 17, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 181. Message in a Bottle, Sept. 26, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 182. Waking Moments (formerly known as Sleep of Reason), Oct. 7, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 183. Hunters (formerly known as Communications), Oct. 16, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 184. Prey, Oct. 27, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 185. Retrospect (formerly known as Mnemonic), Nov. 7, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 186. The Killing Game, Nov. 18, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 187. The Killing Game, Part II, Dec. 1, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 188. Vis à Vis (formerly known as Perspectives), Dec. 12, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 189. The Omega Directive (formerly known as The Omega Effect), Jan. 6, 1998; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 190. Unforgettable (formerly known as Proximity), Jan. 15, 1998; (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 191. Living Witness, Jan. 26, 1998; (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - 192. Demon (formerly known as Demon Rock), Feb. 4, 1998; (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - 193. One, Feb. 13, 1998; (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - 194. Hope and Fear, Feb. 25, 1998; (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Call sheets, Aug. 1994-Apr. 1997; (2 folders) (Box 10)
- Additions, 1999
  Arranged by television series scripts, freelance scripts and development scripts for Norman Lear's Embassy Productions.
  - Television series
    - ABC After School Specials, 1980-1982; (4 folders) (Box 10)
    - Cliffhangers: The Secret Empire, 1979; (4 folders) (Box 10)
    - Cliffhangers: The Panther and the Rose, 1979 (Box 11)
    - Cliffhangers (Box 11)
      Publicity, episode schedules, etc.
    - In the Heat of the Night, 1988; (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - Jake and the Fatman, 1989-1990; (5 folders) (Box 11)
    - Magnum P.I., 1987-1988; (7 folders) (Box 11)
    - Quincy, M.E., 1980-1983; (18 folders) (Box 11)
      Publicity, etc.
  - Freelance
    - California Fever, 1979 (Box 11)
    - The Incredible Hulk, 1980 (Box 11)
    - Little House on the Prairie, 1980-1981; (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - Salvage – 1, 1979; (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Development
    - Body Squad, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Burnout, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Class Act, 1985 (Box 11)
    - Hong Kong Harry, undated (Box 11)
      Story-line only
    - Pandora's Box, 1987 (Box 11)
    - A Place to Call Home (produced as CBS Movie of the Week, ), 1987 (Box 11)
      Script; publicity.
    - The Secret Army of Central Park, 1985 (Box 11)
    - The Secret Life of Agnes Lavianno, 1987 (Box 11)
    - Stanford's 100, 1985 (Box 11)